<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-29T23:48:41-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Melissa Du</title><subtitle>Melissa Du is a recent graduate of Stanford University who studied Computer Science and History. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">How do you think about social responsibility?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/how-do-you-think-about-social-responsibility.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How do you think about social responsibility?" /><published>2018-01-19T16:16:56-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-19T16:16:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/how-do-you-think-about-social-responsibility</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/how-do-you-think-about-social-responsibility.html">&lt;p&gt;How should I live my life? I ask this question a lot because of the following truths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are a finite number of hours in the day, and therefore a finite number of endeavors I can devote my time to. Giving an idea, like trying to become Instagram-famous, equal weight and equal time as something like finding a job for myself post-graduation would be silly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I value certain things more than I do others. I don’t love doing everything, and I need a semblance of happiness and fulfillment in my day-to-day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am lucky. There’s no denying this! I’m not a starving child in a third-world country, and I wasn’t born with a genetic defect that prevents me from thinking or moving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Day-to-day, I don’t work on fighting world hunger, climate change, or deforestation. I don’t work on stopping global war, helping our broken public school system, or the AIDS epidemic. And neither do most of my friends or the people I know. From the comfort of Silicon Valley, life can almost seem pretty great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost easy to ignore the rest of the world from within the Silicon Valley bubble; at Stanford, I’m &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/01/18/upshot/some-colleges-have-more-students-from-the-top-1-percent-than-the-bottom-60.html&quot;&gt;surrounded by privilege&lt;/a&gt; and by working in tech as a software engineer or otherwise, I’ll be working on problems that won’t matter to you at all if, for example, you didn’t have access to clean water (which, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/healthywater/global/wash_statistics.html&quot;&gt;according to the CDC&lt;/a&gt;, is over 35% of the world’s population). Of course, you could make the argument that society is trending towards a direction of technology being increasingly important, not the other way around, and that the technologies that you work on will affect the majority of people in one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow, that doesn’t seem quite satisfying, because if global warming is getting worse and if 13% of our world is undernourished, then why am I not working on those problems? Why isn’t anyone I know working on those problems? (It is also entirely possible that I do know people who are working on these problems, and that I just don’t know about them/their stories. Feel free to prove me wrong!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to conclude these thoughts by posing a few questions. To anyone reading this, I’d love to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What drives you in your current pursuit(s)? Why are you doing what you’re doing?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you think about the amount of social responsibility you have for the world around you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email me if you have any thoughts. I’d love to hear them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How should I live my life? I ask this question a lot because of the following truths:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Airports, Awe, and My Evolving Sense of Consciousness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/05/airports-and-awe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Airports, Awe, and My Evolving Sense of Consciousness" /><published>2018-01-05T16:16:56-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-05T16:16:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/05/airports-and-awe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/05/airports-and-awe.html">&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, airports were my favorite place in the world. They never failed to fill me with a sense of wonder: all of these busy people running to their various destinations! How important this place must be. How important these people looked! I loved hurrying with my family through the crowded avenues of the airport. I felt like I was part of a team; together we made our way past security, deciphered the confusing dashboards with flight times, and finally located the departure gate after meandering past restaurants and ridiculously expensive stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of the airport was the baggage claim, an exciting game in which I scrambled to collect all of my family’s bags while avoiding the countless red herrings the luggage chute threw my way. I looked at each of the different suitcases that tumbled out of the chute with excitement: no, this bag is not the right color, no, mine has a dent in the top left corner…And when one of my family’s bags eventually did come out, I’d chase after it with glee: here it is, Dad, I’ll get it for us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as I step off of a 12-hour flight in Beijing, I’m reminded of my child-like awe and wonder I felt every time I stepped foot inside an airport. These feelings are incredibly at odds with my current mood, however, and it’s hard to retain any sort of glee as I battle long customs lines, intrusive security pat-downs, and incomprehensibly slow lines as I approach the ticket counter to check-in for the next leg of my flight. Instead of admiring the eclectic groups of strangers rushing to their destinations, I now notice how rude people are to each other, pushing and shoving and angrily glaring at their phones. These strangers no longer seem so mystical and important; no, they’re just like me: sleep-deprived because of a 12-hour plane ride in which the stranger in front of them slept in their lap the whole time, cranky because they’re hungry, and impatient because they just can’t wait to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps growing up means being imbued with a sense of consciousness and understanding about the world the around you. People aren’t so nice after all, and the hustle and bustle of the airport is no longer mystical but draining. I wonder if it’s possible to re-acquire my childhood-like sense of wonder about the world around me. Especially in our world today, in which reprehensible moves are made by the people who theoretically should be the most respectable, I want to hold on to my idea that the world is a beautiful, magical place and look beyond all the faults that I’ve come to know and become so familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, I want to remember that our world is a beautiful place. People surprise each other in often the most unfamiliar and beautiful ways. We work together to create intricate systems and groundbreaking technologies. Most importantly, regardless of where I grew up, who I know, or what I believe, I want to remember that I am just as human as any of the other 7.6 billion people on this earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to not forget those things. And I hope that, despite my increasing pessimism, I don’t lose my wonder and awe of the amazing potential we have to work together to create beautiful things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I was younger, airports were my favorite place in the world. They never failed to fill me with a sense of wonder: all of these busy people running to their various destinations! How important this place must be. How important these people looked! I loved hurrying with my family through the crowded avenues of the airport. I felt like I was part of a team; together we made our way past security, deciphered the confusing dashboards with flight times, and finally located the departure gate after meandering past restaurants and ridiculously expensive stores.</summary></entry></feed>