<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-03T13:16:21-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Melissa Du</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Notes on the Beijing tech scene</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/07/02/notes-on-the-beijing-tech-scene.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notes on the Beijing tech scene" /><published>2019-07-02T21:14:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-02T21:14:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/07/02/notes-on-the-beijing-tech-scene</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/07/02/notes-on-the-beijing-tech-scene.html">&lt;p&gt;I just came back from a week in Beijing and wanted to write down some observations while they were still fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#996&quot;&gt;996&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#edtech&quot;&gt;Education Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chuangye&quot;&gt;Entrepreneurship Road&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#logistics&quot;&gt;Logistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#wechat&quot;&gt;WeChat (of course)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#people&quot;&gt;The absurd number of people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#photos&quot;&gt;Some photos, just for fun 🙂&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beijing is currently one of three major tech hotspots in China (the other two being Shanghai and Shenzhen) and houses some of the world’s most valuable start-ups such as Baidu, Didi, and Meituan. More than 1/3 of all VC deals in China are made in Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time Beijing is also one of the oldest cities in the world. It’s been the capital of China for more than 3,000 years and houses some of the world’s most important historical wonders — the Great Wall, the Forbidden City, Tiananmen Square — as well as two of the best universities in all of China — Tsinghua and Peking University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to say Beijing is an important place in the world would be an understatement. The tech scene in Beijing (but also the rest of China) has been developing rapidly in the past ten years and even more so in the past few. The below are some notes on what I observed during my time there in June 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;996&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;996&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People in China work &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. The typical worker embodies a working culture dubbed “996”: nine AM to nine PM, six days a week. This is the expectation amongst young people entering the tech workforce and has been established as the norm by leaders such as Jack Ma (CEO of Alibaba) and companies such as JD.com (an e-commerce company worth about 68B USD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’ve read about a lot of backlash to 996 online, the young people that I met were quite accepting of the 996 work culture (granted, this may also have been sample selection bias). They acknowledged the difficulties but also knew 996 culture was expected and were willing to put in the efforts required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;edtech&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Education Technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the exponential rise of companies like &lt;a href=&quot;www.vipkid.com&quot;&gt;VIPKid&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;www.zuoyebang.com&quot;&gt;Zuoyebang&lt;/a&gt; in the past two years, education technology seems to be a hot area for Chinese start-ups right now. New online platforms are taking advantage of high-quality video-conferencing technologies to instantly connect students with teachers and are going head-to-head with more traditional industry leaders such as New Oriental, which currently has a market cap of about $16B USD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly what hasn’t changed is Chinese people’s willingness to spend their discretionary income on K-12 education, probably in large part due to the rigor imposed by the gaokao (高考) system. Newer startups in the education technology area are now finding ways to apply AI to better adaptively teach children skills across a variety of different areas like English, music, and coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;chuangye&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Entrepreneurship Road&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is literally a road in the middle of Zhongguancun (the neighborhood in Beijing where most startups and VCs are located) called Entrepreneurship Road (创业路). The various people I reached out to when there were all very excited to meet and exchange ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some odd reason I had this mistaken belief that the way startup offices look/feel are unique to Silicon Valley…but it as turns out the startup offices in Beijing look just the way they do here in the Bay Area. 😂 There’s also plenty of WeWorks around Beijing as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;logistics&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Logistics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logistics network in China is incredibly developed, much more so than here in the US. I think a significant barrier in the States is that labor is expensive, so ordering food on DoorDash feels like a luxury that isn’t even worth it since delivery fees can be around $10 and the waiting time is usually almost an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in China labor is cheap and abundant, and the logistics network makes everything instantaneous. Food ordered on an app arrives instantly, and even beyond food you can instantly order literally &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; your heart desires straight to your home: a haircut, cleaning services, an art teacher, sliced fruit…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, just for fun, here’s a photo of some workers I saw organizing packages for delivery on the side of the road. I’m not sure if this is the usual workflow for sorting packages, but I thought it was interesting. 
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../imgs/packages.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;wechat&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;WeChat (of course)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any post on China would be incomplete without a mention of WeChat. This time, though, I learned a few new things about WeChat I didn’t know before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WeChat Mini Programs are apps that exist within the WeChat ecosystem. This allows you to accomplish almost everything you could ever need your mobile phone to do without ever having to leave WeChat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A lot of restaurant’s menus are being replaced by WeChat. Each table is equipped with a QR code, and your food will arrive within a few minutes after scanning the code and placing your order within the restaurant’s WeChat Mini Program.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WeChat only lets you view first-degree connections among your network. Social networks here in the States have popularized the idea of a 2nd-degree network so much that I’ve taken it to be the norm (Facebook’s mutual friends, Twitter’s “Followers you may know”, etc), but WeChat is a completely locked down environment. You can’t request to join any WeChat groups you’re not already a part of, and you can’t add anyone unless you know their phone number or WeChat ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;people&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The absurd number of people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t ever really get used to just how many people there are in China. Rush hour on the trains/buses is insane, and Beijing traffic seems to be bad at all hours of the day. If you thought waiting in line for brunch in San Francisco was bad, here is a photo of the line (at a non-rush hour time) at HeyTea, a very popular tea spot in China: 
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../imgs/heytea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some photos of a crowd of people waiting to watch the flags being lowered at Tiananmen Square: 
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../imgs/crowd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../imgs/square.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;photos&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;And finally, some photos of some delicious food I had in Beijing, just for fun…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../imgs/breakfast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../imgs/duck.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I just came back from a week in Beijing and wanted to write down some observations while they were still fresh.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Everyone should learn sales</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/10/everyone-should-learn-sales.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everyone should learn sales" /><published>2019-02-10T16:16:56-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-10T16:16:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/10/everyone-should-learn-sales</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/10/everyone-should-learn-sales.html">&lt;p&gt;Broadly speaking, people’s skills fall into two areas: “hard” skills and “soft” skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hard skills can be used by the individual who possesses them to actually produce something, such as a mathematical model predicting snowfall in a certain region or a piece of software to analyze restaurant orders. Because hard skills are quantifiable (I can weld X horseshoes in Y amount of time), development of one’s hard skills is also quantifiable (this year I can weld Z% more horseshoes than I did last year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One’s hard skills can only truly be appreciated and evaluated by others who also possess those same hard skills, since only other people who have also spent years training and developing those same hard skills can really understand the legitimacy of that person’s contributions. Crucially, this means that most people cannot properly evaluate “hard” skill contributions. While anyone is able to evaluate the final product created, only a select few — those other people with the same hard skills — will deeply understand the technical effort, breakthroughs, and progress made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that there is a gap between individuals who possess hard skills and everyone else. Soft skills are what can be used by individuals who possess hard skills to bridge that gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike hard skills, soft skills can’t actually be used to create anything. You cannot write a piece of code by being persuasive or build a table by being charismatic. Soft skills are qualitative and vary from person to person. Whereas not everyone possesses hard skills, everyone possesses soft skills. This means that the barrier to entry for feeling like an expert with regards to soft skills is quite low or even non-existent: everyone feels that they know how to judge and evaluate other people, and everyone feels like their judgements and evaluations are correct (at least to some degree). Many people, such as VCs/other investors, even make a living from evaluating other people’s soft skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The true value of soft skills lies in the fact that they can be used to motivate others who have hard skills to create and build things they would not have otherwise. I call this the “ability to sell”. The ability to sell is the ability that contributes most to a person’s success and yet is one of the most under-valued skills in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people in Silicon Valley are highly technical and are not interested in developing the skill of selling. Because the barrier to entry is seen as too low (anyone can sell things, but not anyone can write a highly complex piece of software), most technical people simply aren’t interested. Technically difficult problems with high barriers to entry are much more alluring to people with hard skills, especially since they had to work for years to get to a point where they could even solve those problems in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this to say: the most valuable skill one can possess, especially in a highly technical environment like Silicon Valley, is the ability to sell another person something*. The greatest leaders sell others on their vision of what the world should be and convince other really smart people, often people with the most highly specialized and sought after hard skills, that they should help make that vision into a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &lt;em&gt;While great sales ability can get you really far, it is crucial that the sales is actually based in some sort of reality. Infamous scam artists such as Elizabeth Holmes (Theranos) or Billy McFarland (Fyre Festival) reached the heights of success because of their incredible sales ability. Eventually everything came tumbling down, but there is something to be said about their ability to create billions of dollars in value based on thin air!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Broadly speaking, people’s skills fall into two areas: “hard” skills and “soft” skills.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How do you think about social responsibility?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/how-do-you-think-about-social-responsibility.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How do you think about social responsibility?" /><published>2018-01-19T16:16:56-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-19T16:16:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/how-do-you-think-about-social-responsibility</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/19/how-do-you-think-about-social-responsibility.html">&lt;p&gt;How should I live my life? I ask this question a lot because of the following truths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are a finite number of hours in the day, and therefore a finite number of endeavors I can devote my time to. Giving an idea, like trying to become Instagram-famous, equal weight and equal time as something like finding a job for myself post-graduation would be silly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I value certain things more than I do others. I don’t love doing everything, and I need a semblance of happiness and fulfillment in my day-to-day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am lucky. There’s no denying this! I’m not a starving child in a third-world country, and I wasn’t born with a genetic defect that prevents me from thinking or moving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Day-to-day, I don’t work on fighting world hunger, climate change, or deforestation. I don’t work on stopping global war, helping our broken public school system, or the AIDS epidemic. And neither do most of my friends or the people I know. From the comfort of Silicon Valley, life can almost seem pretty great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost easy to ignore the rest of the world from within the Silicon Valley bubble; at Stanford, I’m &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/01/18/upshot/some-colleges-have-more-students-from-the-top-1-percent-than-the-bottom-60.html&quot;&gt;surrounded by privilege&lt;/a&gt; and by working in tech as a software engineer or otherwise, I’ll be working on problems that won’t matter to you at all if, for example, you didn’t have access to clean water (which, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/healthywater/global/wash_statistics.html&quot;&gt;according to the CDC&lt;/a&gt;, is over 35% of the world’s population). Of course, you could make the argument that society is trending towards a direction of technology being increasingly important, not the other way around, and that the technologies that you work on will affect the majority of people in one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow, that doesn’t seem quite satisfying, because if global warming is getting worse and if 13% of our world is undernourished, then why am I not working on those problems? Why isn’t anyone I know working on those problems? (It is also entirely possible that I do know people who are working on these problems, and that I just don’t know about them/their stories. Feel free to prove me wrong!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to conclude these thoughts by posing a few questions. To anyone reading this, I’d love to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What drives you in your current pursuit(s)? Why are you doing what you’re doing?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you think about the amount of social responsibility you have for the world around you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email me if you have any thoughts. I’d love to hear them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How should I live my life? I ask this question a lot because of the following truths:</summary></entry></feed>